SANJAY KUMAR RATILAL TAMBOLI

A-903, Shivalay Height, Stadium Road, Motera, Sabarmati, Ahmedabad **Ph:** 98254 34 784 (M), **Email:** sanjay_tamboli@yahoo.com, <u>sanjay.tamboli@gmail.com</u>.

IT PROFESSIONAL

OBJECTIVE: Seeking a challenging position in the Information Technology Sector which would provide with opportunities for professional growth, where I can utilize and enhance my experience & acquired technical skills.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS -

Technically astute, result driven and accomplished software professional with 31+ years of brilliant experience successfully delivering on project of various sizes, in multiple domains viz. Banking, Finance, Inventory, Govt Administration, Sales & Marketing and Advertising to diverse range of clients. Last I worked as a **Senior Project Manager with Nascent Info Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Ahmedabad.**

EXPERTISE IN:

- Managing and delivering multiple mobile and web based projects in Java, Microsoft technology and PHP using MS SQL server, Oracle, MySQL and PostGre database.
- > Client interaction for system study, mapping system requirement, conducting system analysis and design for very large ERP for e-governance and banking projects.
- ➤ Huge ERP e-governance and banking project planning / execution, resource allocation / management, task allocation to team members, team supervision / guidance and performance and product reviews to deliver quality project in time.
- Functional specifications and database design ERP e-governance and banking project of large scale.
- > System Design specification, functional testing, system delivery / implementation, walk through and user training for large ERP e-governance and banking project.
- Managing project configuration, software and database installation / up gradation.
- Coordinating with all concerned department like client functional team, web design, technical writer, support team during various stage of project.
- ➤ Played a role of Management Representative (<u>MR</u>) to get the ISO 9001:2008 certificate for Info Stretch Solution Pvt Ltd which includes functions like marketing, software product development, customized software development, software configuration service, quality assurance and quality control, System administration and purchase.
- ➤ Participate in employee recruitment process in consultation with HR dept and pre-sale process in consultation with marketing department to define the tentative scope and time estimation for the project.
- > Setting pre-sale and post-sale process, which takes care of all the activity during sales and project execution
- ➤ Implement new process and improve existing process continuously
- Finalize specification and open source for company product
- Good exposure to ecommerce

I have Sound knowledge of SDLC and software development best practices and the ability to excel within a challenging environment, initiating and executing across a portfolio of projects harmonizing technical needs with business realities. Demonstrated Project Management skills with extensive exposure to broad range of team management activities thrive on working in challenging environment. Planning & co-ordination of all aspects of the project, reviewing project specifications, resource and capacity planning, ensuring a high level of customer support and on-time delivery performance. Strong Leadership to provide direction, motivation and fostering a culture that has high standards of ethics & professionalism.

PARTIAL LIST OF CLIENTS WORKED FOR:

International clients		
ICODE INC. USA	Dragoco, Germany, Singapore	
Singapore airline terminal services, Singapore	Wells Fargo, USA	
E-Dealer, Toronto, Canada.	Info stretch Corporation, USA	

Clarion Technologies Ltd.	Arab Bank for Economic Development in Africa	
Domestic clients		
Citibank N.A., Mumbai	Hindustan lever limited-Mumbai	
Specialty Ranbaxy Ltd, Mumbai	Lintas International (India) Ltd., Mumbai	
Tata Oil Mill Co Ltd, Mumbai	Mother dairy, Gandhinagar	
 Punjab & Sind Bank, Mumbai, Secunderabad 	State Bank of India, Gandhinagar, Mumbai	
 State Bank of Indore, Mumbai 	Punjab National Bank, Mumbai	
 State Bank of Saurashtra, Mumbai, Baroda, 	Nirma Ltd, Ahmedabad	
Bhavnagar		
 Gandhinagar Nagrik Co-operative Bank Ltd 	 Janta Sahakari Bank, Mumbai 	
 Bharat Petroleum Corporation Ltd. 	Directorate of Municipalities, Gujarat	
Shajapur Nagarpalika, Madhya Pradesh	INTAS Bio-Pharmaceutical Ltd., Changodar	
 Text Book Corporation, Madhya Pradesh. 	Government of Gujarat	
BrighTech Fluid Control System, India.	Intellectual property of India	
Vadodara Municipal Corporation	Tourism corporation of Gujarat Ltd.	
 https://www.vtvgujarati.com/ 	https://www.happyfacesfoundation.org/	
Haryana State Industrial & Infrastructure Development Corporation		
Chief electrical inspector and Collector of Electricity duty (HoD of Energy & Petroleum dept.)		
Ahmedabad Municipal Corporation – Heritage City		

Note: Pls., write to me (<u>Sanjay_tamboli@yahoo.com</u>) in case you want to know detail about each project. I will be happy to share detail about each project with you on separate email.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software Skills

4GL Tool Developer 2000, Visual basic (Ver 6), .Net. DotNetNuke, TOAD, Angular 7 (Self study) **RDBMS** Oracle (9i), Micro Soft SQL Server, Paradox (Version 4), Unify, Accell and Ingress

Languages Basic, Cobol, Clipper (Ver 5.2), Fortran, Pascal, C, C++ and UML

Software Dbase III+, FoxPro (Ver. 2.5), Btrieve (Ver 5), Lotus, MS Office, Version control (Novell),

OS & Networks DOS, Unix (AT & T), SMOS (Unix) Ver 7.04 & 8.28, SVR 4.0, Sco Open Server (Unix) Release 5,

Neural Network, Novell, Window NT (Ver 4.0)

Case Tool Oracle Designer 6i, Rational Rose, Micro soft Visio

Hardware Skills

IBM Compatible PCs viz. 286, 386 and 486 IBM NetFinity 5500 with RAID

DDE ORG Super Max (CISC based mini systems, 68030 CPU) Digital Prioris XL6200 Server Intel Pentium Pro

DDE ORG Super Max (RISC based mini systems, R4400 CPU) ICIM team server (RISC based mini systems)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sr. Project Manager Jul 2019 – Feb 2021

Nascent Info Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Ahmedabad.

Sr. Project Manager Oct 2017 – Jun 2019

Silver Touch Technologies Ltd. Ahmedabad.

Project Manager Jun 2012 – Sep 2017

Silver Touch Technologies Ltd. Ahmedabad.

Division Manager Viteb Solution Pvt. Ltd. Ahmedabad.	Feb 2011 – May 2012
Project Manager Infostretch Solution Pvt. Ltd. Ahmedabad.	Oct 2008 – Jan 2011
Project Leader Silver Touch Technologies Ltd. Ahmedabad.	Feb 2004- Sep 2008
Software Consultant Gandhinagar Nagrik Co-operative Bank, Cadila Pharmaceutical Ltd.	Apr 2003- Jan 2004
Oracle Database Consultant GlobalTech (I) Pvt. Ltd.	Jul 2002- Mar 2003
SYSTEMS ANALYST Applitech Solution Ltd. (CMM Level 3)	Jan 2001- Mar 2002
SYSTEMS ENGINEER SPECIALIST DDE ORG Systems Ltd, Ahmedabad	April 1995- Dec 2000
SYSTEMS EXECUTIVE NELCO (S/W Dept), Mumbai	Dec 1994- March 1995
SYSTEMS ANALYST S.A. Industries, Mumbai	Jan 1994- Nov 1994
PROGRAMMING ENGINEER-II Choudhary International–SEEPZ, Mumbai.	June 1993- Dec 1993
PROGRAMMER & SYSTEMS ANALYST Business Solutions, Mumbai	June 1988- May 1993

TRAININGS ATTENDED

Super Max OS (Installation & Basic), DDE ORG Systems Ltd
Integrated Branch Accounting (Banking) System, DDE ORG Systems Ltd
Oracle Forms 6i, DDE ORG Systems Ltd
SAP B1 Introduction

57 II DI Introduction

Project Management Professional Exam Prep Certification Course

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

COURSE IN .NET TECHNOLOGIES

S. S. I., Ahmedabad (2006)

COURSE IN ORACLE (Version .8) & VISUAL BASIC (Version .6) S. S. I., Ahmedabad (2000)

RELATIONAL DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

V. M. C. I., Mumbai (1991)

COMPUTER PROGRAMMING & APPLICATION (Duration: 1 year)

Computer Age, Mumbai (1988)

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (Chemistry)

South Gujarat University (1986)

Additional Information

Date of Birth 11th Dec 1964

References Would be made readily available on request